<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Statistics @ Home</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Statistics @ Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-EN</language>
    <managingEditor>stats.at.home@gmail.com (Justin and Rachel Silverman)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>stats.at.home@gmail.com (Justin and Rachel Silverman)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2017 Justin and Rachel Silverman</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Eternal Sunshine of the Endless Flight</title>
      <link>/2017/06/12/eternal-sunshine-of-the-endless-flight/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>stats.at.home@gmail.com (Justin and Rachel Silverman)</author>
      <guid>/2017/06/12/eternal-sunshine-of-the-endless-flight/</guid>
      <description>I am sitting on a plane from Rome to Philadelphia, marveling at how quickly we can move around the globe. There is a 6 hour time-zone difference between Rome and Philadelphia. My flight took off at 11am in Rome and was set to arrive 9 hours and 45 minutes later at 3:45pm in Philadelphia. This got me thinking, what would your daily schedule look like if you continuously flew west?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fitting Non-Linear Growth Curves in R</title>
      <link>/2017/06/07/fitting-non-linear-groth-curves-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>stats.at.home@gmail.com (Justin and Rachel Silverman)</author>
      <guid>/2017/06/07/fitting-non-linear-groth-curves-in-r/</guid>
      <description>A few months ago I offered to help a friend fit a bunch of microbial growth curves using R. When I was looking over possible solutions I was quite supprised by how little information was available online. Apart from the R package grofit (which after playing around with I decided seemed a little over-designed for my uses) I found very limited recources or code available. As a result of this I wanted to share a few functions I wrote to quickly fit non-linear growth models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2017 Matzah Hunt Potions Puzzle</title>
      <link>/2017/06/04/2017-matzah-hunt-potions-puzzle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>stats.at.home@gmail.com (Justin and Rachel Silverman)</author>
      <guid>/2017/06/04/2017-matzah-hunt-potions-puzzle/</guid>
      <description>For the past 3 years we have put together an event for our friends and family that we have named Matzah Hunt. We put on this event in place of/in addition to a Passover Seder and it is an afternoon and evening full of a series of math/logic puzzles which ultimately lead to a hunt for the Missing Matzah, hence the name, Matzah Hunt. Over the years, the puzzles have become more involved and creative, the decorations have become more elaborate, and luckily, the attendance has grown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sampling Covariance Matricies with Fixed Total Variance</title>
      <link>/2017/06/01/sampling-covariance-matricies-with-fixed-total-variance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>stats.at.home@gmail.com (Justin and Rachel Silverman)</author>
      <guid>/2017/06/01/sampling-covariance-matricies-with-fixed-total-variance/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I have been thinking a lot about the concept of Total Variance recently. Total variance (which can be defined as the trace of a covariance matrix) is a measure of global dispersion that has been particularly useful for me when building multivariate models. However, for some reason, I have yet to see this concept discussed much outside of compositional data analysis (see pg. 35 of Lecture Notes on Compositional Data Analysis) or Principle Component Analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Us</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>stats.at.home@gmail.com (Justin and Rachel Silverman)</author>
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello! And welcome to Stats@Home. We are Justin and Rachel Silverman, PhD students in Statistics and Biostatistics. This blog came out of some creative and statistical musing, side projects, and dissertation tangents. Our goal in writing this blog is to explore some questions or puzzles that we find interesting with a statistical flare.
Some of our statistical interests include machine learning, clinical trials, compositional data, combinatorial analysis, probability theory, but we enjoy all kinds of statistical and probabilistic puzzles.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>