<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Compositional Data Analysis on Statistics @ Home</title>
    <link>/tags/compositional-data-analysis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Compositional Data Analysis on Statistics @ Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-EN</language>
    <managingEditor>stats.at.home@gmail.com (Justin and Rachel Silverman)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>stats.at.home@gmail.com (Justin and Rachel Silverman)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2017 Justin and Rachel Silverman</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/compositional-data-analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Building the ILR from the ALR Transform</title>
      <link>/2017/08/10/building-the-ilr-from-the-alr-transform/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>stats.at.home@gmail.com (Justin and Rachel Silverman)</author>
      <guid>/2017/08/10/building-the-ilr-from-the-alr-transform/</guid>
      <description>Following up on a recent post on limitations of the ALR and Softmax transforms, I wanted to briefly show how we can derive an Isometric Log-Ratio transform from the Additive Log-Ratio (ALR) transform.
The ILR transform is just an orthonormal basis in the simplex with respect to the Aitchison metric (which follows naturally from using log-ratios - I will probably have a post explaining this more in the future). We are going to use the Gram-Schmidt orthonomalization process to build an orthonormal basis given a set of vectors which are not orthonormal (the coordinates defined by our ALR transform).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We can do better than the ALR or Softmax Transform</title>
      <link>/2017/08/09/we-can-do-better-than-the-alr-or-softmax-transform/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>stats.at.home@gmail.com (Justin and Rachel Silverman)</author>
      <guid>/2017/08/09/we-can-do-better-than-the-alr-or-softmax-transform/</guid>
      <description>In multiple places in the Compositional Data Analysis literature (for example here and here) people refer to the Additive Log-Ratio transform (ALR) as “not preserving metric concepts”. But what exactly does this mean and how can we visualize this problem?
Here I am going to briefly describe how this problem can be seen with the ALR transform and then show how the Isometric Log-Ratio (ILR) transform does not have this problem.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>