<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Statistics @ Home</title>
    <link>/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Statistics @ Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-EN</language>
    <managingEditor>stats.at.home@gmail.com (Justin and Rachel Silverman)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>stats.at.home@gmail.com (Justin and Rachel Silverman)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2017 Justin and Rachel Silverman</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Stochastic Loading of Microfluidic Droplets</title>
      <link>/2017/07/08/stochastic-loading-of-microfluidic-droplets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>stats.at.home@gmail.com (Justin and Rachel Silverman)</author>
      <guid>/2017/07/08/stochastic-loading-of-microfluidic-droplets/</guid>
      <description>The Basic Model The First Step - Multinomial Focusing on our Question - Binomial Approximating the Binomial - Poisson  When is the Poisson approximation to the Binomial valid? Looking at Real Parameters Values Calculating the distribution of quantities in light of uncertainty in lab measurements Bivariate Distributions    Droplet-based microfluidics are emerging as a useful technology in various fields of biomedicine. Both droplet digital PCR and droplet based culture methods require that droplets are created with either a single DNA molecule or a single cell per droplet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fitting Non-Linear Growth Curves in R</title>
      <link>/2017/06/07/fitting-non-linear-groth-curves-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>stats.at.home@gmail.com (Justin and Rachel Silverman)</author>
      <guid>/2017/06/07/fitting-non-linear-groth-curves-in-r/</guid>
      <description>A few months ago I offered to help a friend fit a bunch of microbial growth curves using R. When I was looking over possible solutions I was quite supprised by how little information was available online. Apart from the R package grofit (which after playing around with I decided seemed a little over-designed for my uses) I found very limited recources or code available. As a result of this I wanted to share a few functions I wrote to quickly fit non-linear growth models.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>